holos.ie 2017-11-20

# Privacy & Security - Holos.ie

We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of our website visitors; this policy sets out how we will treat your personal information.

**What information do we collect?**

We may collect, store and use the following kinds of personal information:

  * Information about your computer and about your visits to and use of this website (including your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation).
  * Information relating to any transactions carried out between you and us on or in relation to this website, including information relating to any purchases you make of our goods or services.
  * Information that you provide to us for the purpose of registering with us (including your name, address, contact number and email address).
  * Information that you provide to us for the purpose of subscribing to our website services, email notifications and/or newsletters.
  * Any other information that you choose to send to us.

**  
Cookies**

A cookie consists of information sent by a web server to a web browser, and stored by the browser. The information is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. This enables the web server to identify and track the web browser.

We may use both “session” cookies and “persistent” cookies on the website. We will use the session cookies to: keep track of you whilst you navigate the website. We may use the persistent cookies to: enable our website to recognise you when you visit.

When using standard web browser settings, the session cookies will be deleted from your computer when you close your browser. Persistent cookies will remain stored on your computer until deleted, or until they reach a specified expiry date.

Our payment services providers may also send you cookies.

**Using your personal information**

Personal information submitted to us via this website will be used for the purposes specified in this privacy policy or in relevant parts of the website.

We may use your personal information to:

  * Administer the website.
  * Improve your browsing experience by personalising the website.
  * Enable your use of the services available on the website.
  * Send to you goods purchased via the website, and supply to you services purchased via the website.
  * Send statements and invoices to you, and collect payments from you.
  * Send you general (non-marketing) commercial communications.
  * Send you email notifications which you have specifically requested.
  * Send to you our newsletter and other marketing communications relating to our business or the businesses of carefully-selected third parties which we think may be of interest to you by post or, where you have specifically agreed to this, by email or similar technology (you can inform us at any time if you no longer require marketing communications).
  * Provide third parties with statistical information about our users – but this information will not be used to identify any individual user.
  * Deal with enquiries and complaints made by or about you relating to the website.  
We will not without your express consent provide your personal information to any third parties for the purpose of direct marketing.
  * All our website financial transactions are handled through our payment services provider, PayPal. You can review the PayPal privacy policy [here](https://www.paypal.com/ie/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full?locale.x=en_IE "PayPal privacy policy"). We will share information with PayPal only to the extent necessary for the purposes of processing payments you make via our website and dealing with complaints and queries relating to such payments.

**Disclosures**

We may disclose information about you to any of our employees, officers, agents, suppliers or subcontractors insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes as set out in this privacy policy.

In addition, we may disclose your personal information:

  * to the extent that we are required to do so by law;
  * in connection with any legal proceedings or prospective legal proceedings;
  * in order to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights (including providing information to others for the purposes of fraud prevention and reducing credit risk);
  * to any person who we reasonably believe may apply to a court or other competent authority for disclosure of that personal information where, in our reasonable opinion, such court or authority would be reasonably likely to order disclosure of that personal information.

Except as provided in this privacy policy, we will not provide your information to third parties.

**Security of your personal information**

We will take reasonable technical and organisational precautions to prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal information.

We will store all the personal information you provide on secure (password- and firewall- protected) servers.  
Of course, data transmission over the internet is inherently insecure, and we cannot guarantee the security of data sent over the internet.

You are responsible for keeping your password and user details confidential. We will not ask you for your password (except when you log in to the website).

**Policy amendments**

We may update this privacy policy from time-to-time by posting a new version on our website. You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes.

**Your rights**

You may instruct us not to process your personal information for marketing purposes by email at any time. In practice, you will usually either expressly agree in advance to our use of your personal information for marketing purposes, or we will provide you with an opportunity to opt-out of the use of your personal information for marketing purposes.

**Third party websites**

Where our website contains links to other websites, we are not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of third party websites.

**Updating information**

Please let us know if the personal information which we hold about you needs to be corrected or updated.

**Contact**

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or our treatment of your personal information, please write to us by email to [advice@holos.ie](mailto:advice@holos.ie "Email Holos Skincare from Nature") or by post to Holos Skincare from Nature, Enniscorthy Enterprise & Technology Centre, Milehouse Road, Enniscorthy, County Wexford, Ireland.

**Data controller**

The data controller responsible in respect of the information collected on this website is Holos Skincare from Nature.
